Florence Rose Papers, 1832-1970
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL 1903-1970
  - Miscellaneous writings by FR: typescripts, 1943-47, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Letters notifying others about FR's death, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Tributes, 1967-69 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Address books and calendars, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Awards: correspondence, programs, and publicity, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, circa 1903-68, undated (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1923-1968
  - General
    - 1930-39 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1940-49 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1950-59 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1960-69 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Holiday cards, c. 1960s (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Individuals
    - Family
      - Family groups 1967 (Box 3, Folder 6a)
      - Ida Offen (aunt of Rose) and family, 1945-55, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Charles and Jan Rose (nephew of Rose and his wife) circa 1943-1956, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Karen Rose and Joel Miller (niece of Rose and her husband) 1946-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Leon Rose (brother of Rose) 1936-1964, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Katie Rosenblaum (mother of Rose) 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Phil (Felix) Rose[enbaum] (brother of Rose) 1957-1961 (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Rea Rose (sister-in-law or Rose) 1945-1953 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Rebecca [?] (aunt of Rose) (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Anna Wolff (aunt of Rose) 1945-1963, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Friends and associates
      - Anderson, Helen 1966-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Arr, Sophia (Tia) 1943-1959, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Aston, Charles and Laverna 1946-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Atwater, Helen E. 1934-1951 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Bacon, Elizabeth 1941-1969, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Baldwin, Ruth 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Banner, Illa 1968 (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Barotz, Kate 1942-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Beard, Mary 1937, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Benjamin, Hazel 1938 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - Blackford, Grace 1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - Blatch, Harriot Stanton undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
      - Bloom, Cricket and Ben 1944-1958, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - Borg, Mary 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Brandes, Elsie 1947, 1953, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 15)
      - Brashear, Roma 1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - Brush, Dorothy Hamilton 1937-1954 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Buck, Pearl 1934-1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - Buckman, Rilma (Elba) 1941-1967, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Burch, Guy Irving 1935-1945 (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - Burden, Jean 1956-1968, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
      - Burrows, Fred 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 22)
      - Bychowska, Ellen 1955-1958 (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - Chamberlain, Ernest and Ethel
        - Christmas cards, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
        - 1949-1969, undated (Box 5, Folder 2-5)
      - Chou, Anna 1946-1948 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Clyde, Ethel 1934-1965, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Cole, Carolyn, 1936-67, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Cook, Aldelaide Pearson, 1925-65, undated (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
      - Cooper, Tommie, 1965-67 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Cowles, Fleur, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Cox, Harold, 1935 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Cyon, Françoise, 1936-45 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Damon, Cele, 1936-50, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Dana, Pauline, 1934-35 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Darwin, Bess, 1932-67, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Davidson, Doris, 1933-51, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Davis, Edna Rael, 1933-67, undated (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
      - Delp, Mildred, 1941-52, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - de Vries, Lini, 1946-53, undated (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - Dock, Florence, 1937-55 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Douglas, Emily, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Dryden, Maude, 1954-57 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Duke, Mary Alice, 1932-54, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Ellis, Havelock, 1935-39 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Feyling, G.T., 1966-67 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Freeburg, Victor, 1931-34, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Gamble, Dr. Clarence J., 1938-53, 1964, undated (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Gigli family, 1942-65, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - Gimble Brothers, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - Goldman, Emma, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - Goldman, Sylvia, 1945-67, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - Gordon, Dorothy 1954-67, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - Grierson, Margaret, 1946-66 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - Gutman, Daisy, 1961-67 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Hamilton, Bonita, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Hart, A.L. Jr., 1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Hersey, Harold, 1936 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Higgins, Nan (Margaret Sanger's sister), 1936-41 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Holland-Rantos Co., 1923-44, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Hughston, Mary, 1935-36, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Human Betterment Foundation, 1943-44 (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Huse, Penelope (Husey), 1940-49, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Johnson, Mary Worley (Compy), 1943-56, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Kamaladevi, Madame, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Kato, Shidzue, 1933-57, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Krishnamurti, J., 1936, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Kross, Anna Moscowitz, 1936-47 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Lader, Lawrence, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Levine, Sara, 1931-38, undated (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Little, Bea, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Longstreth, Barbara, 1965-68, undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Maazel, Marie, 1941-42, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
      - Macaulay, Mary, 1940-68, undated (Box 7, Folder 26-27)
      - MacCormick, Austin H., 1936 (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Manning, Eddie and Lucille, 1953-54 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Martin, Thomas, 1943-65 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - McGraw, Clara Louise, 1929, 1934 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - McKinnon, Edna Rankin, 1940-66, undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - McNamee, Dorothy and Grace, 1963-66 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Mitchell, Daisy, 1935-67, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Moore, Hazel, 1933-48, undated (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
      - Moore, Sigrid and Harry, 1967-68 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Moorehouse, William, 1965-67 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Morgan, Mary, 1936-56, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Morrell, Dorothea, 1945-48, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Morris, Dr. Woodbridge E., 1941, undated (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Newlin, Dika, 1943-51 (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Newman, Elizabeth, 1950, undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Oterson, Viola G., 1946-47, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Paschal, Marion, 1935-46, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
      - Perry, Mary, 1940-50 (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - Phillips, Anna Jane, 1936-37, undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - Pilpel, Harriet, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - Polk, Elizabeth, 1946-65 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Posner, Henriette, 1929-57, undated (Box 9, Folder 1-3)
      - Price, Betty, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Prieu, Rhoda, 1932-53, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Prizek, Lenore, 1946-47, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Puckle, Betty, 1940-66, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Rama Rau, Dhanvanthi, 1953-56, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Remont, Ruby (graphologist), 1937-43 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Reyneau, Betsy Graves, 1946-67, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Ripley, George and Katie, 1938-56, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Rose, Kenneth, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - Sanger, Grant, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Sanger, Margaret, [see also SERIES IV. SUBJECTS - Margaret Sanger]
        - 1930-39 and circa 1930s (Box 10, Folder 1-8)
        - 1940-47 (Box 11, Folder 1-9)
        - 1948-66, undated (Box 12, Folder 1-8)
        - Letters of appreciation, 1932-66 (Box 12, Folder 9)
        - Greeting cards, 1957-59, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Shuman, Anna Jane, 1942-66, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Skala, Lilia, 1958-68, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Slee, J. Noah H., 1931-38, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Smith, Charles, 1942-43 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Smith, Frances and Oscar, 1931-46, undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Stoecker, Helen, 1942-43 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Stone, Abraham and Hannah, 1937-38, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Stout, Janet Whitenack, 1944-52, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Taynton, Ruth "Rufus," 1934-68, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1931-38 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Voorsanger, Elkan and Henrietta, 1939-69, undated (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
      - Warner, Marie, M.D., 1952-62 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Watumull, Ellen, 1951-66, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Wells, Herbert George, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Wiltshire, Kay, 1943-52, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
- SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS AND ACTIVITIES 1921-1968
  - Birth control activities
    - American Birth Control League
      - By-laws, constitution, histories, principles and aims, and resolutions, 1921-37 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1921-30 (Box 14, Folder 2-5)
      - Board of Directors: agenda and minutes, 1937-39 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Conferences and meetings
        - Annual meeting: invitations, publicity, and summary, 1923-39 (Box 14, Folder 7)
        - First American Birth Control Conference: correspondence and organizing committee minutes, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 8)
        - First National Conference on Birth Control: press releases, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 9)
        - First Pennsylvania Conference on Birth Control: correspondence, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 10)
        - International Congress on Birth Control: correspondence, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 11)
        - Middle Western States Birth Control Conference: contacts, correspondence, invitations, programs, publicity, and tickets, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 12)
        - New York State Birth Control Conference: correspondence, invitations, and publicity, 1924 (Box 14, Folder 13)
        - Sixth International Conference on Birth Control: correspondence, program, printed speech, and questionnaire, 1924-25 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence, 1921-32, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - Fundraising
        - General: lists, reports, and solicitations, 1922-24, 1935, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
        - Clinic campaign: correspondence and lists, 1931-39 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - Legislative work: correspondence, publicity, summaries, and report, 1923-24, 1938, undated (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Lectures and speeches: publicity and typescripts, 1923-36, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Memoranda, 1938 (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - National Medical Council on Birth Control: list, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - Publications
        - Articles: typescripts and printed versions, 1929-38, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
        - Birth Control Review: back issues and solicitations, 1935-39, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
        - Newsletters, 1923-24 (Box 15, Folder 3)
        - Pamphlets, 1927-38, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Publicity
        - Book promotions, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
        - Lists and press releases, 1929-34, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Report, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau [later called Margaret Sanger Research Bureau]
      - General: memoranda and summary, 1923, undated (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Conferences: announcement, correspondence, drafts, lists, and programs, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Contacts: lists, 1938-39 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1936-38, 1969, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Film script for The Biology of Conception and the Mechanisms of Contraception, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Fundraising: lists, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Publications: articles and pamphlets, 1926-38, 1943, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Publicity: correspondence, leaflets, and press releases, 1929-39, undated (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Reports, 1928-43 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Speeches, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Staff: lists, 1937-38 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Birth Control Council of America: minutes, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Birth Control Review: correspondence, printed material, and typescripts, 1917-22 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Birth Control Worldwide News Service: abstracts, correspondence, memoranda, and news reports, 1937-39 (Box 15, Folder 21-22)
    - Citizens Committee for Planned Parenthood: correspondence and press releases, 1939 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - International Planned Parenthood Federation (incorporates the following British birth control organizations: International Committee on Planned Parenthood, National Birth Control Association, Birth Control International Information Centre, Birth Control Investigation Committee, and the Society for the Provision of Birth Control Clinics)
      - Annual reports, 1938-42 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Memoranda, 1937 and 1966 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Minutes, 1958 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Publications
        - Newsletters, 1934-66 (Box 16, Folder 6)
        - Pamphlets, 1930s-52 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Speaker's notes, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Maternity Research Council: correspondence, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - National Committee on Federal Legislation for Birth Control
      - Annual reports, 1934-36 (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - Descriptive memoranda, 1934 (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 16, Folder 12)
        - 1931 (Box 16, Folder 13)
        - 1932 (Box 16, Folder 14)
        - 1933 (Box 16)
        - 1934 (Box 16)
        - 1935 (Box 16)
        - 1936
          - Jan-Mar (Box 16, Folder 15)
          - Apr-Dec (includes Dorothy Kenyon, Leonard Boudin) (Box 16, Folder 16)
        - 1937 (Box 16, Folder 17)
        - 1938 (Box 16, Folder 18)
        - undated (Box 16, Folder 19)
      - Conferences and events
        - American Conference on Birth Control and National Recovery: announcement, program, and summaries, 15-17 Jan 1934 (Box 16, Folder 20)
        - "Birth Control Comes of Age" dinner, 12 Feb 1935
          - Planning material: budget, drafts, lists, minutes, research, suggestions, and worksheet, 1934-35 (Box 17, Folder 1)
          - Correspondence (includes Harriot Stanton Blatch), 1934-35 (Box 17, Folder 2)
          - Publicity: newspaper clippings, notices, and press releases, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 3)
          - Speeches, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 4)
          - Memorabilia: guest list, invitation, messages, proceedings, program, and summaries, 1935 (Box 17, Folder 5)
        - Dinner in honor of H.G. Wells: program, 23 Oct 1931 (Box 17, Folder 6)
        - National meeting: program, 28 Oct 1930 (Box 17, Folder 7)
        - Western States Conference on Birth Control and Population Poblems: newspaper clippings and program, 20-23 Feb 1930 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Endorsements: lists, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Fundraising: lists, 1931, 1936-37 (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
      - Legal proceedings
        - Bills
          - S. 4582 introduced in the Senate of the United States, seventy-first Congress, second session, 26 May 1930 (Box 17, Folder 12)
          - S. 4436 introduced in the Senate of the United States, seventy-second Congress, first session, April 21, 1932 (Box 17)
          - H.R. 11082 introduced in the House of Representatives of the United States, seventy-second Congress, first session, May 26, 1932 (Box 17)
        - Briefs
          - U.S. v. One Package of Japanese Pessaries and Dr. Hannah Stone, U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals, second circuit, 1936 (Box 17, Folder 13)
          - U.S. v. John P. Nicholas and U.S. v. Norman E. Himes, U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals, second circuit, 1938? (Box 17)
        - Cases: correspondence, memoranda, newspaper clippings, notes, and summaries, 1932-42, undated (Box 17, Folder 14)
        - Transcripts
          - Hearings of the Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, seventy-first Congress, third session, on S. 4582, Feb 13-14, 1931 (Box 17, Folder 15)
          - Hearings of the Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, seventy-second Congress, first session, on S 4436, May 12-20, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 15)
          - Hearings of the Subcommittee of the Committee on the Judiciary, United States Senate, seventy-third Congress, second session, on S 1842, March 1, 20, and 27, 1934 (Box 17)
      - Outreach campaign to doctors and social workers: correspondence, drafts, and lists, 1933-37 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Publications
        - Articles: reprints and typescript, 1929-37, undated (Box 18, Folder 1)
        - National Birth Control News, 1936-37 (Box 18, Folder 2)
        - Newsletters, 1931-36 (Box 18, Folder 3)
        - Pamphlets, 1933-37, undated (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Publicity: charts, flyers, leaflets, press releases, and radio broadcast transcript, 1932-37, undated (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Special reports
        - Meeting reports: lists, procedures, and summaries, 1935-36 (Box 18, Folder 6)
        - Summary reports, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 7)
        - Interviewers' reports
          - Benjamin, Hazel, 1935-36 (Box 18, Folder 8)
          - Countryman, Helen, 1935-36 (Box 18, Folder 9)
          - Fuhr, Lee, 1935-36 (Box 18, Folder 10)
          - Hamilton, Ruth, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 11)
          - Rose, Florence, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 12)
          - Miscellaneous interviewers, 1936-37 (Box 18, Folder 13)
          - Tabulation of interviews, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Speeches, 1936 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - National Committee for Planned Parenthood: list, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Planned Parenthood Federation of America (known as the Birth Control Federation of America from 1938-Mar 1942)
      - Founding documents: correspondence, minutes, objectives, printed material, and reports, 1938 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - National organization
        - General: typescripts and printed material, 1939-40 (Box 19, Folder 3)
        - Administration: affiliation standards, bylaws, constitution, minutes, objectives, personnel policies, and proposals, 1942-43 (Box 19, Folder 4)
        - Budget, 1941-42 (Box 19, Folder 5)
        - Program, 1944 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - State organizations
        - General: agendas, lists, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, and proposals, 1940-55 (Box 19, Folder 7)
        - Alabama: publicity, 1940? (Box 19, Folder 8)
        - Colorado: proposal, 1941 (Box 19, Folder 9)
        - Connecticut: annual report, bulletin, correspondence, memoranda, newspaper clippings, and publicity, 1939-41 (Box 19, Folder 10)
        - Florida: analysis and summary, 1938-41 (Box 19, Folder 11)
        - Kentucky: analysis and posters, 1941, undated (Box 19, Folder 12)
        - Massachusetts: editorial, memoranda, and newsletters, 1938-41 (Box 19, Folder 13)
        - Michigan: publicity, 1934-40 (Box 19, Folder 14)
        - Minnesota: correspondence, minutes, program, and publicity minutes, 1939-42, undated (Box 19, Folder 15)
        - New Hampshire: annual letter, 1939 (Box 19, Folder 16)
        - New Jersey: correspondence and newsletters, 1939, undated (Box 19, Folder 17)
        - New York: agendas, newsletters, and typescript, 1939-42, undated (Box 19, Folder 18)
        - North Carolina: printed material and program outline, 1939-40, undated (Box 19, Folder 19)
        - South Carolina: magazine article and printed material, 1940, undated (Box 19, Folder 20)
        - Tennessee: budget and correspondence, undated (Box 19, Folder 21)
      - Board of Directors: agendas, lists, and minutes, 1939-45, undated (Box 19, Folder 22)
      - Committees
        - Clergymen's: agendas, contacts, correspondence, lists, memoranda, minutes, newspaper clippings, printed material, proposals, publicity, reports, resolutions, and sermons, 1930, 1939-43, undated, [see also flat file] (Box 19, Folder 23-24)
        - Public Progress: correspondence and publicity, 1938-43, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
        - Personnel Practices: lists, minutes, policies and recommendations, 1939-41 (Box 20, Folder 2)
        - Doctors': minutes, 1939 (Box 20, Folder 3)
        - Executive: minutes, recommendations and reports, 1940-45 (Box 20, Folder 4)
        - Field: drafts and memoranda, 1942-43 (Box 20, Folder 5)
        - Legal: correspondence, drafts, memoranda, and recommendations, 1942-43 (Box 20, Folder 6)
        - Medical: memoranda and minutes, 1942-43 (Box 20, Folder 7)
        - Program: minutes, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 8)
        - Public Information: agenda, memoranda, publicity, and resolution, 1942-43 (Box 20, Folder 9)
        - Social Work Advisory: memoranda and minutes, 1943 (Box 20, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1939-44, undated
        - 1939-40 (Box 20, Folder 11)
        - 1941 (Box 20, Folder 12-16)
        - Jan-Jun 1942 (Box 21, Folder 1-11)
        - Jul-Dec 1942 (Box 22, Folder 1-7)
        - 1943-50, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - Departments
        - General: weekly activities reports by Florence Rose, 1939-43, undated (Box 22, Folder 9-10)
        - Negro Services
          - Budgets, 1941-42, [see oversize box 36] (Box 22)
          - Committees
            - National Advisory Council: activities summary, correspondence, and lists, 1939-42 (Box 22, Folder 11)
            - National Negro Sponsoring: lists, 1941-42 (Box 22, Folder 12)
            - Planning Committee on Negro Problems: agenda, list, and minutes, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 13)
          - Contacts
            - General, 1942-43 (Box 22, Folder 14)
            - Jeanes teachers, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 15)
            - Service providers: lists and report, 1941-42 (Box 22, Folder 16)
          - Correspondence, 1941-45, undated (Box 23, Folder 1-7)
          - Educational activities: correspondence, lists, printed material, and publicity, 1930-43 (Box 23, Folder 8-10)
          - Memoranda, 1940-43 (Box 24, Folder 1)
          - Proposals, 1938-43, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
          - Publications: drafts, newsletters, and pamphlets, 1941-43, undated, [see also Educational activities] (Box 24, Folder 3)
          - Publicity: newspaper clippings, photograph, and press releases, 1940-43, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
          - Reports
            - Annual: correspondence, drafts, and outline, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 5)
            - Consultants', 1942-45 (Box 24, Folder 6)
            - Field work, 1944 (Box 24, Folder 7)
            - Summary and progress, 1942-45 (Box 24, Folder 8)
            - "Highlights of 1944-45 Program" on work with Negroes: printed material, 1945 (Box 24, Folder 9)
            - Miscellaneous, 1941-42, undated (Box 24, Folder 10)
          - Research
            - Pamphlets, 1930-42 (Box 24, Folder 11-12)
            - Papers and articles, 1932-42, undated (Box 24, Folder 13)
            - Miscellaneous: lists and typescript, 1940-44, undated (Box 24, Folder 14)
        - Public Information
          - Program, 1939-41 (Box 25, Folder 1)
          - Annual report, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 2)
          - Catholic campaign: correspondence, memoranda, notes, and reports, 1939-43, undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
          - Report on Washington meeting, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 4)
          - Press release presentations, 1942, undated (Box 25, Folder 5-6)
        - Medical: lists and report, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - Events
        - Annual dinner "Population Planning in a Better World": announcement, program, seating list, and speech, 1942 (Box 25, Folder 8)
        - Annual meeting: summary and program, 1941 and 1955 (Box 25, Folder 9)
        - Birth Control and Civil Liberties dinners: press releases, 1941 (Box 25, Folder 10)